

Anjali Kulkarni

Location: Pune, Maharashtra, India

Phone: +91-9890550858

Email: anjaliyogeshkulkarni@gmail.com

Medium: @anjaliyogeshkulkarni

LinkedIn: anjalikulkarni **GitHub:** anjaliyogeshkulkarni

Skills

Java, Python, ShellScript

Selenium, Cucumber, RESTAssured TestNG, JMeter, SeleniumGrid

AWS, Docker, Jenkins, GitLab

ISTQB, Certified Scrum Master

Education

B.E.(Instru), Cummins College, Pune May 1999

Diploma in Advanced Computing, CDAC, Pune August 2000

Profile Summary

Over 18 years of experience as a Principal Architect QA and Technical Manager, leading multiple teams across diverse domains with a focus on client-facing responsibilities. Currently working as a solopreneur, providing consultancy and training services for both students and corporate clients.

Employment History

Trainer, C-DAC, Pune

May 2014 - Present

- Software Engineering
- Testing Methodologies
- QA Automation UI (Selenium) + API
- Python Basics & Advanced

Principal Architect QA, Xoriant, Pune May 2017 - Aug 2024

Domain: Mortgage

Developed automation frameworks for UI and API automation (Java, Selenium, Cypress, and Cucumber), framework for parallel execution by leveraging AWS services (Python, AWS Lambda, AWS Step Functions, DynamoDB, and S3 buckets). Handled a client facing role of technical manager for multiple Dev and QA teams.

QA Manager, PierianDx, Pune Sep 2015 – Apr 2017

Domain: Genomics

Designed framework for UI and API automation (Python, Java, Selenium, Cucumber) with parallel execution using headless browser (Selenium Grid & PhantomJS) along with CI/CD setup (Jenkins)

Senior Team Lead, PubMatic, Pune May 2013 – Sep 2015

Domain: Digital Advertising

Led QA team for UI and API automation and regular testing of the web application and APIs. Performance testing - JMeter

Test Lead, GS Lab, Pune Dec 2005 – Apr 2008

Domain: Identity Management

Designed UI automationframework (AutoIT) while leading QA Team.

System Engineer, CXO Systems, Pune Sep 2004 – Sep 2005 Led automation effort for desktop / Web UI (Silk Test). Created a report generator for consolidating test results using PERL.

QA Engineer, Nihilent, Pune Nov 2002 – Jul 2004

Domain: Banking

Led the QA effort and also built an automated report generator using PERL for bringing in operational efficiency

QA Engineer, Kale Consultants, Pune Jul 2000 – Oct 2002

Domain: Banking, Healthcare

Automating desktop applications using Rational Robot and Silk Test.

Honors

- Nominated as Women Tech Maker Ambassador by Google, India
- Presented research on use of Generative AI in Software Testing
- Regular speaker at Conferences and Meetups
- Avid interest in Chess and Yoga